nrelate.com 2014-06-29

# Privacy | nrelate

Your browsing history on sites with a nrelate plugin is being used to generate your recommendations.  
If you would not like nrelate to use your browsing history, [click here](http://nrelate.com/opt-out.php). 

**Privacy Policy**

Welcome to nRelate.com, a Website owned and controlled by nRelate, LLC., a subsidiary of IAC, Inc. (“nRelate”, “we”, “us”, or “our”).  We operate a platform through which websites and other platforms can display other content owners’ work – including articles, product reviews, videos and blog posts.   This helps website owners to provide relevant third party content to their users.  When you see web content (usually thumbnails at the bottom or side of a page) that says “About These Links” and click on that link, you may see a pop-up box that identifies the content as being placed with our help.  Our mission is to help websites, applications and other services use their free space show content that is both relevant and interesting, while also subsidizing their own (usually free) content.

We provide this privacy policy to let you know what information we collect from you, and how we use, share and protect it.  We refer to the content that we help display as “Content Links.”

**Scope**

This Privacy Policy applies to the website located at [www.nRelate.com](http://nrelate.com/) (the “nRelate Website”), the tools and interactive forums made available through the nRelate Website and the nRelate content-sharing platform (collectively the “Services”).

Generally, there are three categories of users of the nRelate Website and Services: “Publishers” who are operators or publishers of websites that make the nRelate sharing platform available on their own website, “Marketers,” who display their content across our platform, and “Users” who are individuals that visit a website.  By visiting the nRelate Website or using the Services, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy governs two sets of data practices:

[Privacy Practices for Users of the nRelate Services and Content Links](http://nrelate.com/privacy-policy/#section2)

**2. nRelate Services Content Choices and Opt-Out**

We believe that delivering targeted and relevant content enhances your internet experience.As we describe further in this Privacy Policy, we (or a partner we work with) may collect non-personally identifiable information from the websites that use the nRelate Services, including information about your browser, device, or IP address, and we (or our partner) may collect and use that information to avoid showing you the same content multiple times on Publishers’ websites, or to deliver content we think is relevant to you based on the content you have clicked on in the past on Publishers’ or other websites.If you prefer that we do not collect this information about your website visits for the purpose of delivering targeted advertising, you may [opt-out.](http://nrelate.com/opt-out.php)

If you opt out, we will place an opt-out cookie on your computer.  The opt-out cookie tells us not to use your information for customizing content we serve.  This may mean, for instance, that you may receive the same content multiple times rather than receiving new or targeted content.  Please note that if you block cookies, our opt-out process may not function properly. Please also note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, clear your cookie cache, update your browser, or if you go online with a different computer or internet browser, you will need to renew your opt-out choice.

**3.  ** **Privacy Practices for End Users Who Click and View nRelate Content Links:   The Data We Collect and How We Use and Share It.**

As part of the Service, we operate the nRelate platform, which helps website owners provide more relevant third party content to their users. If you are reading this policy, you are probably familiar with the way that nRelate helps content owners display their content on other websites.  When you click on Content Links that is enabled on one of our Publisher websites, we collect certain non-personally identifiable information automatically for use on our platform. We may enable Publishers to use all of some of this information through the Platform for analytics purposes and we also may use this information for customizing Content Links to you, as described below.

**(a)  ** **The Information We Collect When You View Content Links**

When you click and view Content Links we may collect certain Non-Personally Identifiable Information about you.  Non-Personally Identifiable Information is information that generally cannot by itself be used to identify who you are on an individual, personal level.  We may collect, retain, and use for analysis information including:

i. The type of browser and operating system you have used to access the website;

ii. Your IP address (which is a number automatically assigned to your computer when you access the Internet and can be used to   derive    your general geographic location);

iii. The website you visited before clicking and viewing Content Links, or that you viewed while clicking and viewing Content Links;

iv. Information about the Content Links you view and how you use the Services, including what you click and view, how long you view it.  We may collect or store this information by using [cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies.](http://nrelate.com/privacy-policy/#section4) You can learn more about these online technologies in Section 4 below;

v. Other information that you voluntarily submit to us.

**(b)  ** **How We Use the Information We Collect When You View Content Links.**

We may use the above information for the following purposes:

i. To customize the content we display to you, including building relevant data segments based on what you click and view (e.g., enjoys movies, enjoys sports);

ii. To better understand how the Service is being used and improve the Service;

iii. To help us ensure that the Service is functioning properly;

iv. For ad delivery and reporting purposes;

v. For any other purpose disclosed to you at the time we collect your information.

**(c)  ** **How we Share the Information We Collect When You View Content Links.**   We may share information collected relating to the Content Links, as follows:

**i.  ** **Affiliates and Partners**.  We may share your information with our affiliates — companies that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with nRelate — as well as select partners and service providers.  You may view this list of affiliates [here](http://www.iac.com/brands).  These entities may, for instance, use your information to make or help us make predictions about your interests, and may provide you with offers, promotional materials, and advertisements.

**ii. Service Providers**.  We may share your information with entities that provide services to us, including companies that provide payment processing, customer and web support, web analytics, data processing, data enhancement and customer insights, advertising, email distribution, and other services.

**iii. Other Parties When Required by Law or as Necessary to Protect Our Services**.  We may disclose your information to other parties in order to:

  1. protect the legal rights of nRelate, its affiliates, and sites or services we work with;
  2. protect the safety and security of our users, ourselves, or any other person or entity;
  3. prevent fraud (or for risk management purposes); or
  4. comply with or respond to the law or legal process or a request for cooperation by a government entity, whether or not legally required.

**iv.    Other Parties in Connection With a Transfer of Assets**.  If we make a sale or transfer of assets, or are otherwise involved in a merger or transfer, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, we may transfer your information to third parties as part of that transaction.

**v**.    In addition, we may aggregate your Non-Personally Identifiable Information with the Non-Personally Identifiable Information of others and share that aggregated information with third parties without restriction, including with Publishers and Marketers, such as for analytics purposes or to help them learn more about their customers and users.

**4. Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies**

nRelate uses a variety of technologies to learn more about how people interact with our Website and Services.  This section provides more information about some of those technologies and how they work.

**(a)  Cookies**.  Cookies are small text files that websites and other online services use to store information about users on the users’ own computers. For instance, cookies can be used to store sign-in credentials so that you don’t have to enter them each time you return to a website, or to store other information to make web viewing more customized or efficient upon future visits.  Cookies also may store a unique identifier tied to your computer so that web services and content and advertising networks can recognize you across visits to different websites.  You can configure your internet browser to warn you each time a cookie is being sent or to refuse all or certain cookies completely.

**(b)**   **nRelate may use or support cookies as follows** :

i. To collect information about your browsing activities in order to deliver customized or relevant Content Links, services, or advertising or to you, through its Publishers or this Website;

ii. To relate the information collected by cookies to information we obtain from you directly or from commercially available sources;

iii. To work with third parties that help us serve Content Links (through our Services or across the internet) or provide other services to us, such as providing users the ability to view or comment on content or tracking site usage statistics.

**(c)   Web beacons**. We may use technologies called Web beacons that communicate information from your Internet browser to a web server.  Web beacons can be embedded in web pages, videos, or emails, and can allow a web server to read certain types of information from your browser, check whether you have viewed a particular web page or email message, and determine, among other things, the time and date on which you viewed the Web beacon, the IP address of your computer, and the URL of the web page from which the Web beacon was viewed.  We may use web beacons for a variety of purposes, including to analyze the use of the Services and in conjunction with cookies to provide content that is more relevant to you.  
  
**5. Privacy Practices for Users of this Website**

**(a)**   **The Information We Gather on the Website and How We Use it** :

The nRelate Website itself is primarily directed to Publishers and Marketers, although we welcome Users who want to know more about our Services. When you access the Website or Services, we may collect the following information:

**i.  ** **Personal Information**.  When you set up an account with us (for instance, to sign up as a Publisher), we may request and you may provide certain “Personal Information” to us – that is, is information that may be used to directly contact or identify a person.  This may include your name, postal address, e-mail address, or phone number, and other information associated with this Personal Information.  We collect Personal Information from you when you knowingly provide it, such as when you register as a Marketer or Publisher on the Website, communicate with us and/or or request information.  We use your Personal Information to administer your account and provide you services, to send communications and administrative emails, to respond to your inquiries, and to send marketing and product update messages to those who ask for such messages.

**ii. Non-Personally Identifiable Information**.  Whether or not you sign up for an account or provide us with Personal Information, we may collect other Non-Personally Identifiable Information when you visit our Site.  This may include:

1\. The type of browser and operating system you have used to access the website;

2\. Your IP address (which is a number automatically assigned to your computer when you access the Internet and can be used to derive your general geographic location);

3\. The website you visited before clicking and viewing Content Links, or that you viewed while clicking and viewing Content Links;

4\. Information about the Content Links you view and how you use the Services, including what you click and view, how long you view it,

5\. Other information that you submit to us.

We may collect or store the above information by using [cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies](http://nrelate.com/privacy-policy/#section4).

**(b)  Accessing and Controlling Our Use of Your Personal Information:**

If you have provided Personal Information when registering for our Website, you may access and modify that information at any time by visiting your account settings. While we would be sorry to see you go, you can delete your account at any time by contacting support@nrelate.com. Keep in mind, however, that even if you delete your account, we may retain your Personal Information to comply with laws, prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use, and take other actions otherwise permitted by law. There may be residual Personal Information that remains within our databases, access logs, and other records. In addition, we are not responsible for updating or removing your Personal Information already disclosed to third parties who have been provided information as permitted by this Policy. In addition, You can opt out of receiving certain email communications from the Website by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email. Please note that even if you unsubscribe or opt-out, we may still send you communications related to your use of the Service.

**4.  MISCELLANEOUS TERMS**

**(a)   ** **Information Security, Retention, and Data Integrity**

We take reasonable security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data.  However, no security safeguard is 100 percent foolproof, and we are unable to guarantee that the security measures we take will not be penetrated or compromised or that your information will remain secure under all circumstances.

**(b)   ** **Children**

We do not knowingly collect or maintain Personal Information from individuals who are under 13 years of age, and no portion of our Website or Services is designed to attract people under the age of 13. Protecting the privacy of children is important to us:  if we learn that a user is under the age of 13, we will take steps to remove that user’s Personal Information from our databases.

**(c)  ** **Links to Other Websites**

Our Services contain links to, and allow Marketers to share content on, Publisher Websites and services. The fact that we link to a website or service or allow others to share content on them is not an endorsement, authorization or representation that we are affiliated with that third party, nor is it an endorsement or acknowledgement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. Other websites and services follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

**(d)   ** **International Users**

The Website and Services are hosted in the United States. If you access the Website or Services from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Website or Services, you are transferring your Personal Information to the United States and you consent to that transfer. Additionally, you understand that your Personal Information may be processed in countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing Personal Information may be less stringent than in your country.

**(e)  ** **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us any time through this Website or by writing to us at the address set forth above.

**(f)  ** **Enforcement, Questions, and Complaints**

If you have any inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy, please contact nRelate by emailing us at privacy@nRelate.com or writing to us at:

Privacy Officer  
nRelate LLC

1500 Broadway, 6th Floor

New York, NY 10036

Last Updated: April 10, 2013
